SessionPorter: turn one AI coding session into a portable, privacy-aware bundle. Local-first, sanitized by default, no external AI.
AI sessions are useful development evidence but contain secrets and private paths, and every tool stores them differently.
Discover lists sessions: metadata only, no content, no full paths.
Inspect one selected session by its safe, hashed id.
Preview redactions before anything is written. The report shows counts only, never values.
Export writes the bundle. Sanitized is the default; private mode requires an explicit confirmation.
The bundle: normalized.jsonl goes to AgentTrace; transcript.md goes to an offline Claude conversation; no raw log in sanitized mode.
The transcript carries an honest completeness note. Hidden model reasoning is not reconstructed.
The redaction report lists category, count, and affected events only. It never prints a value.
Every bundle is validated by checksums. A test proves zero network egress. Records are exported, never executed.
Built with Claude Code and review subagents. A portability subagent found AgentTrace ignores a flat category, so the output became AgentTrace-native records.
Local CLI, no database, no cloud, no external model. Codex is experimental. Current-session matching is heuristic. Redaction is heuristic, so review before sharing.
SessionPorter turns one selected AI coding session into a portable, validated, privacy-aware evidence bundle.